Guide to the Thomas Davidson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Thomas Davidson papers
1857-1948
1857-1902
MS 169
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
15
(37 boxes)
Correspondence, lectures, articles, printed matter, clippings, and film relating to the career of Davidson who came to the U.S. in 1867 and was associated with the St. Louis and Concord schools of philosophy, the founding of the Fellowship of the New Life, and the establishment of the Breadwinners' College. From 1878 to 1884, he was in Italy studying the writings of Antonio Rosmini-Serbati, about whom he published a study in 1882. The major portion of the papers is made up of correspondence, including letters from Henry Adams, John Dewey, Oliver Wendell Holmes, William James, Henry Cabot Lodge, John Stuart Mill, and Stephen Samuel Wise. Only a few pages of his diary of 1858 survive. Also with the papers is material from Edward Endelman, a student of Davidson's. Of particular interest is Endelman's correspondence about Davidson with William T. Harris, a Hegelian philosopher who had been a close friend of Davidson's. In addition, two reels of microfilm collected by John Roemischer which contain letters and articles by Davidson in other repositories have been added to the papers.
Davidson, Thomas, 1840-1900
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles M. Bakewell, 1944 and 1956; William A. Kurlane, 1961; Mrs. Edward Endelman, 1959; and John Roemischer, 1975. Also by purchase in 1963.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Writings about Davidson. IV. Miscellaneous Papers and Memorabilia. V. Edward Endelman Papers.
Scope and Contents
In some ways, these papers present Davidson the educator more than Davidson the student of philosophy. Although his scholarly interests are well represented here, in articles, notes, and translations, one is struck by the number of public lectures and popular essays. Even the notes are often drafted in the style of his lectures. The teaching materials in Series II, WRITINGS, and IV, MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS AND MEMORABILIA, and the papers of his student, Edward Endelman, in Series V, serve to reinforce this impression.
The papers are organized as follows: Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, alphabetically arranged; Series II, WRITINGS, alphabetical for the most part; Series III, WRITINGS ABOUT DAVIDSON; Series IV, MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS AND MEMORABILIA; and Series V, EDWARD ENDELMAN PAPERS. Additional Davidson materials are available on microfilm; a listing of these follows the listing of the papers themselves.
Prominent correspondents include Henry Adams, John Dewey, Edward Emerson, William Torrey Harris, Oliver Wendell Holmes, William James, Henry Cabot Lodge, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, John Stuart Mill, Josiah Royce, and Stephen Samuel Wise, but most of the correspondents are not well known. There are only a few of Davidson's own letters in the papers.
Scattered throughout Series II-V are notes and transcripts by John Roemischer and (more frequently) photocopies of Davidson material with Roemischer's annotations. Folders which contain only Roemischer's notes on a Davidson essay, without some form of the essay itself, are identified in the listing by the words "(notes only)."
The papers were given by Charles M. Bakewell, William H. Kurlans, and Edward Endelman. The microfilm was the gift of Dr. Roemischer.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas Davidson: taught Latin and Greek in Tunbridge Wells and Wimbledon, England, 1863-1866; taught and became a principal in the public school system of St. Louis, beginning in 1868; active in circle of Hegelian philosophers in St. Louis; in 1875 moved to Boston and became freelance writer and teacher at private schools; from 1878-1884 spent much time in Italy in close contact with the Rosminian order; in 1883 founded the Fellowship of the New Life in London; later founded a Breadwinners' College in New York City; author of numerous books and articles.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
COMPLETE LIST OF CORRESPONDENTS
Abbe, Robert, 1851-1928 (1) 1900
Abbot, Francis Ellingwood, 1836-1903 (6) 1885-1890
Abbott, Lawrence Fraser, 1859- (1) 1890
Adams, E. P. (3) 1885-1886
Adams, Henry Brooks, 1838-1918 (3) 1876 and n.d.
Adams, Marion (Hooper), 1843-1885 (6) 1875 and n.d.
Adams, Maurice (1) 1883
Addams, Jane, 1860-1935 (1) 1890
Adler, Felix, 1851-1933 (2) 1888, n.d.
Alcott, Amos Bronson, 1799-1888 (15) 1867-1876
Allan, John (10) 1858-1862
Allan, Anne (2) n.d.
Allen, George T. (3) 1873-1874
Allen, James H. (2) 1876
Allen, William Frederick, 1846-1915 (16) 1871-1875
Ames, Charles H. [see also D.C.Heath, Co.] (13) 1884-1898
Amson, Adolf (17) 1871-1877
Amson, Arthur, 1875 (4) 1872-1875
Anagnos, Michael, 1837-1906 (12) 1877
Anderson, Sir Alexander (1) 1863
Anderson, Rasmus Bjorn, 1846-1936 (4) 1875
Angus, John (1) 1863
Appel, Jacob (1) 1870
D. Appleton & Co. (3) 1884-1886
Appleton, Thomas Gold, 1812-1884 (3) 1879-1880
Argyropoulos, S. G. (2) 1878-1886
Armstrong, Fred (2) 1886
Atkinson, Charles C. (2) 1865-1866
Aubingé, Merle d' (1) 1860
Auriol, T. (1) n.d.
Azarias, Brother, 1847-1803 (8) 1890-1892
Aveling, Edward Bibbins, 1851-1898 (1) 1896
Bacon, Katherine P. (1) 1889
Baker, George Hall, 1850-1911 (4) 1891-1892
Bakewell, Charles Montague, 1867-1957 (3) 1895-1898
Baldwin, James Mark, 1861-1934 (2) 1893,1898
Banker, George W. (3) 1885-1890
Baralt, Luis A. (7) 1889-1892
Barclay, James W. (25) 1862-1869
Barker, Mary (9) 1861-1862
Barker, Thomas Richard, 1799-1870 (5) 1860
Barnard, Henry, 1811-1900 [see Kobbé, S. L.]
Barney, Sarah Elizabeth (Brandegee) (42) 1885-1893
Barrack, William (6) 1860-1866
Barrère, Emile (1) 1866
Barrett, Julia Robbins (1) 1885
Bartholomew, George Kellam, 1835- (1) 1873
Barton, Frederic Otis, -1904 (5) 1893-1899
Bax, Ernest Belfort, 1854-1926 (1) 1882
Beedy, Mary E. (42) 1870-1887
Bell, Helen Olcott (Choate), 1830-1918 (79) 1876-1877
Benton, Alexander Hay (2) 1863
Benton, William (1) n.d.
Bernays, Charles L. (7) 1870-1873
Bernays, George I (1) n.d.
Biader, E. (1) 1860
Bibb, Grace C. (20) 1872-1879
Bigelow, Adeline A. (6) 1876-1879
Bindernagel, Katherine (112) 1861-1870
Bishop, J. H. (1) 1860
Bishop, George R. (6) 1884-1885
Black, Adam and Charles, publishers (2) 1882
Black, J.W. & Co. [see photographic artists]
Blair, Apolline (Alexander), 1811-1882 (3) n.d.
Blair, James Lawrence, 1854-1904 (27) 1868-1877
Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882 (1) 1865
Block, Louis James, 1851-1927 (9) 1872-1893
Blow, Susan Elizabeth, 1843-1916 (1) n.d.
Bolivar, T. (1) 1884
Bonafede Carlo (1) 1893
Bonghi, Gigi (1) 1878
Bormida, Giuseppe (2) 1881,1882
Boston Museum of Fine Arts
Boyd, Louise V. (1) 1871
Brackenbury, John M. (1) 1866
Brackett, Anna Callender, 1836-1911 (64) 1867-1879
Bragadin, Giovanni (8) 1883-1884
Brall, Amalie (2) 1863-1865
Brewster, Anne Maria Hampton, 1819-1882 (49) 1878-1885
Brewster, Benjamin Harris, 1816-1888 (1) 1879
Brey, Delia M. (9) 1868-1874
Bridges, John Henry, 1832-1906 (4) 1881
Bridges, Mary A. (1) 1883
Brimmer, Martin, 1829-1896 (5) 1881-1883
Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899 (2) 1890
Brodie, Hughina N. (9) 1861-1863
Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893 (1) 1878
Brown, Adam (2) 1867
Brown, Mary (3) 1866
Browne, Herbert J. [see Shakespeare-Bacon controversy]
Buchner, Ludwig, 1824-1899 (3) 1872-1875
Bundy, John C. (11) 1884-1885
Bullard, Mrs. Stephen H. [see Tutoring]
Burns-Gibson, John (14) 1881-1884
Buroni, Giuseppe, 1821-1885 (1) 1883
Burrows, Herbert (5) 1894
Butler, Charles Augustine Vaughan, 1857-1929 (2) 1881
Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1949 (18) 1887-1898
Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925 (4) 1896-1897
Cabot, Arthur Tracy, 1852-1912 (1) 1896
Cabot, Charles Mills (3) 1888-1892
Cabot, Edward Twisleton, 1893 (10) 1877-1885
Cabot, Elizabeth (36) 1877-1898
Cabot, Elizabeth Rogers (Mason), 1834- (6) 1892-1896
Cabot, F. H. (4) 1885-1888
Cabot, Francis Elliot (3) n.d.
Cabot, Henry Bromfield, 1861-1932 (22) 1882-1892
Cabot, James Elliot, 1821-1903 (34) 1875-1894
Cabot, L. R. (28) 1876-1887
Cabot, Richard (1) 1878
Cabot, Richard Clarke, 1868-1939 (15) 1877-1898
Cabot, Walter L. (4) 1892-1893
Caldwell, Juliet (3) 1873
Calkins, A. M. F. (1) 1883
Calza, J. (3) 1882-1883
Calza, Giuseppe (9) 1880-1884
Campbell, Helen (Stuart), 1839-1918 (21) 1885-1887
Campbell, K. B. (1) 1899
Campbell, Lewis, 1830-1908 (1) 1895
Canada (miscellaneous)
Carpenter, Stephen Haskins, 1831-1878 (2) 1875
Carr, Alfred W. (1) 1884
Carr, Cornelia L. (32) 1875-1885
Catlin, Arnold Welles, 1841-1931 (7) 1885
Catlin, Charles Taylor, 1835-1912 (2) 1885
Catlin, L. A. (1) 1885
Cavazza, Elizabeth (12) 1887-1890
Cavazza, [Nino?] (4) 1880
Cellarius, Frederick (1) 1879
Cestre, Charles, 1871- (1) 1897
Chamberlin, Melissa (1) 1893
Champion, H. H. (2) 1883,1887
Chapman, John, 1822-1894 (2) 1887
Chenoweth, Caroline (Van Dusen), 1846-1890 (1) 1890
Chevaillier, Alzire A. (2) 1890,1893
Chiappelli, Alessandro, 1857- (2) 1897
Chicago Philosophical Society [no folder]
Child, Francis James, 1825-1896 (14) 1879-1890
Child, Helen M. C. (1) 1893
Chittenden, Lucy B. (1) 1885
Christian Literature Co., N.Y. (10) 1897
Chubb, Percival A., 1860- (108) 1882-1898
Clark, Anna Tsinger (1) n.d.
Clark, John Bates, 1847-1938 (1) 1887
Clarke, Joseph H. (4) 1880
Clarke, Sydney (3) 1898-1900
Clarke, William (8) 1882-1884
Clary, P. A. (1) 1866
Class, George (52) 1868-1880
Clement, Clara Erskine [see Waters, Clara (Erskine) Clement, l834-1916]
Clubb, William (50) 1868-1877
Cobb, James T. (4) 1887
Cobb, John Storer, [see Schmidt, L.W.]
Cockerill, John A. [See New York "World"] (3) 1887-1888
Cole, S. E. (7) 1872-1874
Cole, M. E. (2) 1886
Collar, William Coe, 1833-1916 (1) n.d.
Collie and Collie (1) 1862
Comegys, Cornelius George, 1816- (3) 1874-1875
Comments on Davidson's views (Misc)
Committee for the Bruno Monument
Comitti, Enrico (11) 1884-1885
Concord School of Philosophy (1) 1887
Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1832-1917 [see Testimonials]
Cook, Frederick F. (2) 1885,1886
Cope, Edward Drinker, 1840-1897 (10) 1888-1889
Corlies, Susan M. (14) 1882-1892
Cornell, Edith (1) 1886
Cossío, Manuel Bartolomé, l858-1935 (3) 1880
Coste, Felix, Sr. (2) 1874,1876
Coste, Felix, Jr. (9) 1875-1877
Coste, Louise (4) 1886-1892
Coste, Paul F. (42) 1874-1893
Coste, Pauline (10) 1875-1893
Cowie, John and Jean (1) 1841
Cross, Parnell LeB. (3) 1885-1886
D'Abernon, Edgar Vincent, 1859-1931 [missing] (2) 1880
Daley, Charlotte F. (10) 1880-1892
[Dalgleish?], Walter Scott, 1834-1897 (1) 1862
D'Arcy, Henry I (3) 1874
Dana, Ellen (2) 1885
Davidson, G. (2) 1862
Davidson, John Morrison (37) 1860-1889
Davidson, Lewis H. (4) 1892-1897
Davidson, Mary (Warrender) (16) 1860-1883
Davidson, Rose (1) n.d.
Davidson. Sarah Rose (Fowlie) (5) 1867-1894
Davidson, Thomas, 1840-1900 (62) 1851-1899, n.d.
Davidson, William (4) 1886-1887
Davis, Annie (1) 1890
DeHart, John S. (2) 1886
DeHart, M. F. (2) 1887
De la Plaine, Blanche L. (2) 1875
Denison, H. (2) 1865,1866
DeVit, Vincenzo, 1811-1892 (2) 1881,1883
Dewey, John, 1859-1952 (6) 1890-1892
Dewey, Alice (Chapman) (2) 1893,1900
DeWulf, Maurice, 1867- (1) 1897
Dickinson, L. F. (3) 1887
Dillard, James Hardy, 1856- (2) 1886,1887
Doane, James A. (10) 1874-1875
Doerr, Frederick (1) 1874
Doggett, Kate (Newell), 1827-1885 (15) 1875, n.d.
Doggett, William Elkanah, 1820-1876 (1) 1874
Donnelly, Ignatius, 1831-1901 (3) 1887
Draper, Ada A. (24) 1884-1887
Drew, Frank (10) 1892-1897
Dreykorn, J[oannes] (1) 1869
Droppers, Garrett, 1860-1927 (3) 1887-1889
Dudley, Mrs. M. V. [see Sherman, Caroline]
Duncan, Thomas Davidson (1) 1870
Dunhaupt, Rudolph C. F. (3) 1870
Dunstan, Wyndham Rowland, 1861-1949 (19) 1882-1897
Eckardt, Lauritz (1) 1865
Einerman, Heinrich (5) 1863
Eliot, Charles, William, 1834-1926 (1) 1874
Eliot, William Greenleaf, 1811-1887 (3) 1872-1874
Elliott, Aaron Marshall, 1844-1910 (1) 1891
Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939 (9) 1883-1888
Elseffer, Amanda Shaw [see Concord School of Philosophy]
Emanuel, Joseph (1) 1883
Emberson, F. C. (6) 1867
Emerson, Edward Waldo, 1844-1930 (12) 1884-1887
Emerson, Annie Shephard (Keyes), &1928 (1) 1884
England, Scotland (miscellaneous)
Estcourt, Rowland Metzner, 1855- (3) 1844
Evans, Edward Waterman, &1907 (39) 1892-1898
Evans, Richard C. (1) 1867
Fair, John (17) 1889-1900
Fairchild, E. M. (1) 1896
*Fellowship of the new Life, New York, 1 [1887]
Ferrari, Teresa (4) 1882-1885
Ferri, Luigi, 1826-1895 (14) 1880-1894
Ferrier, David, 1843-1928 (2) 1880,1882
Fethers, Ogden Hoffman, 1847-1911 (5) 1871-1874
Fisher, Edward Thornton, 1836- (4) 1885
Fitts, William B. (16) 1897-1898
Fitzgerald, Caroline (1) n.d.
Foote, Edward Bond, 1854-1912 (4) 1887-1892
Forster, Mary (4) 1893
Forum, The (11) 1887-1898
Foster, Annie H. (3) 1887-1892
Foster, Edith B. (1) 1892
Foster, Marion G. (1) 1886
Foster, R. Norman (16) 1886-1893
Fowler, Robert (10) 1863-1865
Fowler & Wells [see Phrenological Reading of Thos. Davidson]
Free Religious Society (5) [1887, 1891]
Free Thought Education (4) [1885-1887]
French, Frances Graham, -1919 (1) 1894
Frothingham, Arthur Lincoln, 1859-1923 (2) 1890
Frothingham, Ellen, 1835-1902 (2) n.d.
Fruchto, A. C. (1) 1888
Fuller, Mary S. (2) 1890
Fulton, Jefferson L. (3) 1893
Fulton, E. F. (Mrs. Jefferson L.) (1) 1893
Fulton, Lester (1) 1893
Fyfe, John (7) 1862-1882
Gairns, John R. (1) 1874
Gall, Alexander (80) 1860-1868
Gardiner, Harry Norman, 1855-1927 (52) 1887-1900
Gardner, Dorsey, 1842-1894 (3) 1868
Garrigues, Gertrude (1) 1887
Garrison, Wendell Phillips, 1840-1907 (1) 1884
Gay, Erastus (1) 1889
Geary, M. R. M. (2) 1866-1867
Geddes, James Cruickshank (Cruikshank?) (1) 1855
Geddes, Rachel Blanche (2) 1884
Geddes, Rachel Robertson (White) (4) 1882-1884
Geddes, Sir William Duguid, 1828-1900 (10) 1857-1884, n.d.
Free Thought Education (4) [1885-1887]
George, Henry,1839-1897 (9) 1884-1887
Gibbens, Margaret (13) 1883-1897
Germany miscellaneous
Gildersleeve, Basil Lanneau (Laurence?) 1831-1924 (8) 1879-1884
Gilfillan, Grace (2) 1873,1892
Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908 (5) 1876-1889
Ginn, Edwin, 1838-1914 (87) 1872-1888
Ginn and Co. (15) 1872-1897
Glidden, Mary E. [see Mary E. (Glidden) Irvine]
Goddard, E. B. (1) n.d.
Goddard, Delano Alexander, 1831-1882 (3) 1877-1880
Goddard, Martha Howland (LeBaron),1829-1888 (245) 1875-1888
Goldmark, Susan (3) 1892
Goodwin, William Watson, 1831-1912 (6) 1872-1892
Gourlay, Reginald (3) 1867-1868
Greece miscellaneous
Greenough, James Bradstreet, 1833-1901 (4) 1876-1886
Gregoriis, Giuseppe de (7) 1884
Grey, Maria Georgina (Shirreff), 1816-1906 (7) 1884-1887
Grier, W. Fisher (30) 1899
Grierson, Charles Henry, 1855- (2) 1874
Grierson, Alice (Kirk) -1888 (1) n.d.
Grierson, Benjamin Henry, 1826-1911 (1) 1874
Griggs, Edward Howard, 1868- (27) 1887-1898
Groos, Karl, 1861- (1) 1873
Grove, James (1) 1882
Grubb, Arthur O. (2) 1872,1873
Grubb, Sophie F. (15) 1872-1881
Guse, Karl (1) 1875
Haig, Isabella [missing] (1) 1873
Haeckel, Ernst Heinrich Philipp August, 1834-1919 (1) 1869
Halbherr, Federico, 1857-1930 (6) 1882-1884
Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909 (1) 1882
Hall, Granville Stanley, 1844-1924 (3) 1884-1887
Halsted, Leonora B. and Nellie (7) 1885-1886
Hardy, Mary C. (2) 1888
Harlow, William M. (3) 1874-1876
Harnisch, A. E. (2) 1884
Harris, David H. (3) 1873
Harris, Edward M., 1841- (2) 1876
Harris, William Torrey, 1835-1909 (20) 1872-1899
Harrison, Caskie (7) 1876-1887
Hassaurek, Friedrich,1832-1885 (1) 1875
Haydock, Hannah W. (1) n.d.
Hazard, Rebecca N. (18) 1872-1891
Heath, D.C. and Co. (32) 1886-1899
Hedge, Frederic Henry, 1805-1890 (2) 1886
Hellmuth, Isaac, 1817-1901 (2) 1886
Henderson, G. D. (1) 1865
Henry, J. F. (10) 1874-1875
[illegible]
[illegible]
Hight, George B. (19) 1875-1890
Hillard, Katherine, 1839-1915 (8) 1884-1887
Hinton, Margaret (Haddon) (1) 1883
Hirschfield, Martin L. (1) 1886
Hitchcock, Henry, 1829-1902 [see under tutoring]
Hobart, E. F. (1) 1872
Hodgson, Richard, 1855-1905 (5) 1889-1890
Hodgson, Shadworth Hollway, 1832-1912 (4) 1881-1898
Holbrook, Martin Luther, 1831-1902 (3) 1886-1891
Holland, Frederick May, 1836-1908 (3) 1884-1886
Holmes, James H. (1) 1872
Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894 (1) 1873
Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935 (1) 1880
Holy, Fanny (3) 1872
Hooper, Franklin William, 1851-1914 (14) 1885-1892
Hopkinson, John Prentiss, -1914 (1) 1874
Horix, August (9) 1870-1875
Houghton, Mifflin & Co. (20) 1888-1890
Hovey, Harriette Farnham (Spofford) (1) 1891
Hovey, Richard, 1864-1900 (9) 1888-1892
Howe, Julia (Ward), 1819-1910 (3) 1893-1896
Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920 (8) 1874-1878
Howison, George Holmes, 1834-1917 (15) 1864-1881
Howison, Lois Thompson (Caswell) (1) 1869
Hoyle, Irving F. (4) 1884-1892
Hubbard, Gardiner Greene, 1822-1897 (3) 1896-1897
Huebner, Louis (1) 1875
Hunicke, Felix (20) 1875-1877
Hunicke, H. August (5) 1874-1875
Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892 (6) 1878-1888
Hutchison, Keith M. (2) 1871
Hyndman, Henry Mayers, 1842-1921 (2) 1886
Hyslop, James Hervey, 1854-1920 (7) 1888-1891
Ianovics, Annie (2) 1893, n.d.
Ianovics, Gräfin (i.e, Countess) (2) 1880
Irwine, Mary E. (Glidden) (12) 1873-1889
Italy miscellaneous
Jaegerhuber, Max (3) 1872
James, Alice Howe (Gibbens) [missing] (1) 1888
James, William, 1842-1910 (26) 1880-1900
Jamieson, George, 1815-1903 (6) 1860-1863
Jerome, William Travers, 1859-1934 (1) 1890
Johnson, Thomas Moore, 1851-1919 (18) 1875-1897
Johnson's Universal Cyclopedia (2) 1893-1895
Johnston, Alexander (23) 1859-1885
Jones, Richard, 1855-1923 (1) 1897
Judson, Isaac N. (15) 1885-1891
Jupp, William J. (6) 1883-1885
Kavanagh, Francis Edge (1) 1890
Keane, John Joseph, 1839-1918 (1) 1892
Keith, A. B. (2) 1873
Keller, A. von (1) 1874
Kellogg, Alice A. (1) 1890
Kemlo, Alexander (5) 1862-1865
Kemp, Edith (2) 1889
Kent, Annie (11) 1888-1896
Kerr, David (1) 1860
Kesson, E. L. (1) 1861
King, George, 1840-1909 (11) 1860-1865
Kirchner, Charles F. (1) 1875
Kirchner, William H. (5) 1873-1875
Kitchin, George William, 1827-1912 (2) 1866
Kitching, Edith Howard (19) 1888-1896
Kitching, Harriet B. (8) 1884-1885
Kitson, E. (1) 1868
Kittredge, George Lyman, 1860-1941 (1) 1898
Knight, William Angus, 1836-1916 (8) 1882-1897
Kobbé Sarah Lord (Sistare) (1) 1889
Koehler, Sylvester Rosa, 1837-1900 (4) 1880-1881
Kroeger, Adolph Ernst, 1837-1882 (4) 1870
Lampros, Spyridon P., 1851-1919 (3) 1881
Landreth, Burnet (3) 1886
Lathrop, Rose (Hawthorne), 1851-1926 (2) 1885
Latimer, E. (1) 1865
Lanciani? (1) 1878
Laurie, Simon Somerville, 1829-1909 (1) 1898
Lavatelli, P. A. (1) 1881
Lawton, William Cranston, 1853-1941 (1) [See Library of World's Best Literature] n.d.
Lazzaridis, Giorgio (4) 1883-1884
Learned, John Calvin, 1834-1893 (2) 1873
Learned Societies
Lee, Henry, 1817-1898 [see Tutoring]
Lee, Joseph. 1862-1937 (14) 1884-1889
León, Albert J. (14) 1892-1897
Leonardos, Basileios Joannes (23) 1878-1896
Leprince, Augustin (1) 1866
Leprince, Sara Elizabeth (1) 1888
Leslie, Andrew (10) 1871-1891
Leslie, James, -1871 (1) 1865
Library of the World's Best Literature (7) 1896-1898
Liefde, Jacob de (2) 1864-1865
Liefde, John Sr. de (1) 1865
Liefde, John Jr. de (22) 1862-1865
Lighthall, William Douw, 1857- (2) 1890
Lincoln, David Francis, 1841-1916 (2) 1877,1888
Lindeman, Edward O. (3) 1873-1874
Lippman, Morris J. (13) 1876-1884
Lippman, Guida. H. (6) 1883-1893
Little, Arthur Eugene, 1854- (91) 1871-1879
Little, Mary Evelina, 1860- (1) 1875
Livingston, Carrie Way (1) 1888
Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903 (11) 1888-1893
Locke, Clinton, 1829-1904 (1) 1891
Lockhart, William, 1820-1892 (100) 1880-1892
Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924 (2) 1875,1879
Lolli, Arcangelo (17) 1882-1884
Long, Claude H. (22) 1867-1880
Longfellow, Alice Mary (1) n.d.
Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882 (4) 1867-1876
Longfellow, William Pitt, 1836-1913 (2) 1879-1880
Longfellow, Samuel, 1819-1892 (1) n.d.
Longmuir, A. D. (4) 1864
Longmuir, John, 1803-1883 (1) 1862
Lowe, Edwina Dean (1) 1873
Lowe, Oscar F. (1) 1875
Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891 (1) 1876
Lowson, D. L. (2) 1884, 1888
Luedeking, Robert (7) 1867-1875
Lutoslawski, Wincenty, 1863-1955 (1) 1899
Lutsche, Julius (11) 1864-1865
MacAlister, James, 1840-1913 (2) 1890,1892
McAnally, David Rice, Jr. (9) 1871-1874
McCombie, Annie (3) 1861,1863
McCombie, May (52) 1861-1872
McCombie, William, 1809-1870 [see Testimonials]
MacDonald, William. G. (1) n.d.
MacDonald, Robert [see Shakespeare-Bacon Controversy]
MacDonell, Helen (5) 1861-1862
McDonell, James, 1842-1879 (84) 1860-1863
McHardy, Alexander Burness, 1842- (1) 1862
McKendrick, John Gray, 1841-1926 (16) 1863-1865
McKendrick, Mary (Souttar) (2) 1863
McKenzie, J. I. (1) 1867
McKenzie, J. Alexander (2) 1879,1888
Mackey, Peter Paul (2) 1883
Mackie, David (3) 1863-1882
McLean, Matilde (2) 1893
MacPherson, Robert, 1806-1867 (2) 1860,1862
McTaggart, John. Ellis, 1866-1925 (2) 1894,1895
Mair, Catherine (2) 1861,1862
Mair, Edward.? ? (1) 1869
Mamiani (della Rovere?), Terenzio (Counte?), 1799-1885 (7) 1880-1884
Mann, Prestonia (13) 1890-1894
Mann, Ann R. F. (1) 1896
Manning, A. G. (1) 1867
Mansfield, Alfred, 1834- (1) 1872
Mansfield, Helen (24) 1872-1874
Mansfield, Mary (7) 1872
Margolis, Max Leopold, 1866-1932 (6) 1892
Marinangeli, Domenico (3) 1878-1883
Marquand, Allan, 1853-1924 (3) 1890
Marseilles, Charles (3) 1884-1887
Marvin, Joseph B. (3) 1867-1871
Masante, Luigi (1) 1880
Matthews, W. T. (1) 1867
Matz, Mary L. (1) 1893
Mead, Edwin Doak, 1849-1937 (9) 1884-1887
Mearns, Jacob (3) 1898-1900
Medberry, James Knowles (1) 1868
Mendes, Henry Pereira, 1852- (14) 1897-1900
Mercer, George Gluyas, 1853-1906 (1) 1899
Merwin, James Burtis, 1835- (1) 1869
Metsakes, Joannes D. (2) 1878
Michie, Caroline (17) 1867-1869
Middlemore, Samuel G. C. (9) 1880-1883
Mill, John Stuart, 1806-1873 (1) 1866
Miller, R. M. (5) 1885-1887
Miller, Mary M. (1) 1886
Mills, Charles DeB.
Milne, E. A. (1) 1882
Milne, William (2) 1863
Mitchell, Ellen M. (7) 1884-1892
Moncrieff, W. G. (1) 1866
Moncrieff, Helen (17) 1867-1875
Montgomery Edmund Duncan, 1835-1911 (11) 1884-1889
Moore, Fillmore, 1856- (25) 1887-1893
Moore, George Foot, 1851-1931 (1) 1887
Moore, Morris (1) 1878
Moors, John Farwell, 1861- (3) 1888-1890
Morgan, James Appleton, 1845-1928 (2) 1887
Morgan Ella Smith (Mrs. Horace Hills Morgan) (1) 1869
Morgan, Harrietta (2) 1900
Morgan, Horace Hills (18) 1868-1884
Morgan, Mary (8) 1888-1890
Morley, John, 1838-1923 (2) 1881,1882
Morris, Charles D'Urban, 1827-1886 (2) 1869,1870
Morrison, Archibald (2) 1862
Morrison, David (1) 1861
Morse Sidney H. (24) 1866-1869
Moses, Bernard, 1846-1930 (1) 1875
Mullany Patrick Francis, 1847-1893 [missing] (8) 1890-1892
Muller, Charles F. (3) 1860
Münsterberg, Hugo, 1863-1916 (2) 1894,1898
Münsterberg, Selma (Oppler) (1) 1894
Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1830-1910 (1) 1891
Murker, John (28) 1859-1866
Murray, John Clark, 1836-1917 (6) 1890-1893
Murray, Rosa (7) 1888-1892
Nadaud, Martin (4) 1865-1867
Nagy, Albino (3) 1894-1896
Neil, Robert Alexander, 1852-1901 (1) 1884
Newton, Richard Herber (17) 1886-1898
Nichols, Fannie P. (6) 1885-1888
Nichols, Blanche (1) 1887
Nichols, Samuel B. (7) 1884-1885
Nimmo, James (28) 1861-1864
Nino, [Antonio de?] (23) 1878
Noa, Henriette (2) 1870,1873
Noble, George Washington Copp (1) 1867
Noble, Elizabeth (Halsted), &1894 (2) 1875,1885
Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908 (2) 1867,1879
Nunzio, Padre (10) 1882-1884
O'Brien, William Desmond (1) 1889
O'Connor, Josephine [see Photographic Artists]
O'Connor, William Douglas, 1832-1889 (1) 1888
Oldring, A. (1) 1892
Orange Summer School (2) 1887
O'Reilly, Helen B. (20) 1872-1876
O'Reilly, Thomas (1) 1876
Overbeck, Johannes Adolf, 1826-1895 (6) 1875-1882
Palmer, Courtlandt, 1843-1888 (4) 1885-1888
Palmer, Frederic, 1848-1932 (8) 1876-1878
Palmer, George Herbert, 1842-1933 (1) 1875
Paoli, Francesco (1) 1881
Parkinson, H. T. (1) 1883
Parsons, Eugene, 1855-1933 (4) 1894-1895
Partridge, Charles C. (1) 1885
Partridge, William Ordway, 1861-1930 (173) 1885-1900
Passfield, Sidney James Webb, baron, 1859-1947 (1) 1894
Paul, Charles Kegan, 1828-1902 (22) 1880-1885